When Shade's good, she's very good. But when Trudi's bad, she's better.
Gas Food Lodging is a drama, romance film directed by Allison Anders.
Nora, a single mother raising two teenage daughters, Shade and Trudi, waits
tables at a truck-stop diner in a small New Mexico town.
The beautiful and rebellious Trudi drops out of school and gets a job alongside Nora,
while the younger Shade whittles away her time at Spanish movie matinees.
Their lives are turned upside down when Trudi becomes
pregnant and the girls' absent father returns.
Nora, played by Brooke Adams.
Trudi, played by Ione Skye.
Shade, played by Fairuza Balk.
John Evans, played by James Brolin.
Dank, played by Robert Knepper.
Hamlet, played by David Lansbury.
Gas Food Lodging is a 1992 American drama film written and directed by Allison
Anders, based on the novel Don't Look and It Won't Hurt by Richard Peck.
Starring Brooke Adams, Ione Skye, and Fairuza Balk, the film follows a waitress trying to find romance
while raising two daughters in a trailer park in a small desert town in New Mexico.
Gas Food Lodging premiered at the Sundance Film Festival in January 1992, where it was nominated for the Grand Jury Prize, and was
screened at the 42nd Berlin International Film Festival on February 24, 1992, where it was nominated for the Golden Bear.
The film was theatrically released in the United States
on July 10, 1992, to critical acclaim.
At the 8th Independent Spirit Awards, Balk won for Best Female Lead, while the film earned nominations in four other
categories, Best Film, Best Director, and Best Screenplay for Anders, and Best Supporting Female for Adams.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship, waitress,
parent child relationship, new mexico, diner.
The tone is emotional.